I'm going to run each piece of example code and see what it does.
سأقوم الآن بتشغيل كل جزء من التعليمة البرمجية المثال .وأرى ما سيتم تنفيذه
The first piece of code involves adding a series to a square data frame.
يتضمن الجزء الأول من التعليمة البرمجية .إضافة متسلسلة إلى إطار بيانات مربع
That is, a data frame with the same number of rows as columns.
أي إطار بيانات .يحتوي على صفوف وأعمدة بنفس العدد
I've used 0, 1, 2, and 3 as both the index values and the column names here.
وقد استخدمتُ 0 و1 و2 و3 كقيم مؤشرات .وأسماء أعمدة على حد سواء هنا
I've printed out both the original data frame, and
وقد طبعتُ إطار البيانات الأصلي
the result of adding the series here for comparison.
ونتيجة إضافة المتسلسلة هنا على حد سواء .لإجراء المقارنة
It looks like the value 1 was added to each value in the first column,
ويبدو أن القيمة 1 قد أُضيفت ،لكل قيمة في العمود الأول
2 was added to each value in the second column, and so on.
بينما أُضيفت 2 لكل قيمة في العمود الثاني .وهكذا
So it looks like each value from the series was added to one of
ولهذا السبب يبدو أن كل قيمة من المتسلسلة قد أُضيفت إلى أحد
the columns of the dataframe.
.أعمدة إطار البيانات
Given this, I have an idea what will happen if I add a series to a dataframe
وفي ضوء هذا، لدي فكرة بما سيحدث إذا أضفتُ متسلسلة لإطار بيانات
with a single row.
.به صف واحد
But I'll try it anyway.
.ولكني سأجربها بأي طريقة
Again, I've printed both data frames here for comparison, and
وأكرر، لقد طبعتُ إطاري البيانات هنا لإجراء المقارنة
again it looks like each value from the series was added to a single column
ويبدو أن كل قيمة من المتسلسلة قد أُضيفت إلى عمود واحد
from the data frame.
.من إطار البيانات
1 was added to the first column, 2 was added to the second column and so on.
حيث أُضيف 1 .للعمود الأول، بينما أُضيفت 2 للعمود الثاني وهكذا
Something that might not be obvious given this is what will happen if I add
وهناك شيء قد لا يظهر في ضوء هذا وهو ما الذي سيحدث إذا أضفتُ متسلسلة لإطار بيانات
a series to a data frame with only one column?
به عمود واحد؟
Will it figure out somehow that it should add the values to
هل ستكشف بعض الشيء أنه من اللازم إضافة القيم
each row of the data frame instead?
لكل صف من إطار البيانات بدلاً من ذلك؟
I tried it out here, and you can see that's not what happened.
لقد حاولتُ هذا هنا .ويمكنك أن ترى أن هذا ما لم يحدث
Instead, the result of the addition actually has four columns, one for
وبدلاً من هذا، كانت نتيجة إضافة القيم بها أربعة أعمدة بالفعل أي عمود واحد لكل قيمة في
each value in the series, and every column except the first contains NaNs.
المتسلسلة وكل عمود .باستثناء العمود الأول، يحتوي على NaN ،
The first column had 1 added to each value, as before.
يحتوي العمود الأول على .1 مضافة لكل قيمة كما سبق
By the way, the code df.add s it's usually the same as df plus s,
وبالمناسبة، تتطابق التعليمة البرمجية df.add s مع ،التعليمة البرمجية df plus s
so I usually don't call this function.
.ولهذا السبب لا أسمي ذلك دالة
But the benefit of using this function is that it can also take
ولكن ميزة استخدام هذه الدالة هي أنها تحتوي على
an axis argument.
.وسيطة محور
If I use axix = columns, I get the same result as df plus s.
،إذا استخدمتُ axix = columns .سأحصل على نفس نتيجة استخدام df plus s
However if I use axis='index' then each value of the series will be added to
ومع ذلك، إذا استخدمتُ axis='index' ستُضاف كل قيمة من المتسلسلة إلى صف واحد
one row of the data frame, which might be what I want in some cases.
من إطار البيانات وهو ما .يكون المقصود في بعض الحالات
Now in all the examples I've tried so far, the index of the series has been
والآن في جميع الأمثلة التي جربتُها حتى الآن تطابق مؤشر المتسلسلة
the same as the column names of the data frame, 0, 1, 2, and 3.
مع أسماء أعمدة إطار البيانات .0 و1 و2 و3
Now I'm going to look at an example where that's not the case.
والآن سأُلقي نظرة على مثال .لم يكن كهذه الحالة
Here the index of the series is B,C, D, and E and
في هذا المثال نجد أن مؤشر المتسلسلة هو B وC وD وE وأسماء الأعمدة بإطار البيانات هي
the column name of the data frame are A, B, C, and D.
A وB وC .وD
The result here is very similar to what happened when we added Pandas series and
تتشابه النتيجة في هذا المثال إلى حد كبير جدًا مع ما حدث عندما أضفنا متسلسلة Pandas
the indexes didn't match exactly.
.ولم تتطابق المؤشرات بدقة
For each letter that wasn't present in both the data frame and
بالنسبة لكل حرف لم يكن موجودًا في إطار البيانات والمتسلسلة
the series, the result is NaN.
.على حد سواء، فإن النتيجة هي NaN
For letters that were present in both,
،وبالنسبة للحروف التي كانت موجودة في كليهما
the addition has been matched up based on letter.
تمت مطابقة الإضافة .حسب الحرف
So every value in the b column has had 1 added to it and
وبهذا الشكل تمت إضافة 1 لكل قيمة في العمود b
1 was the value in the series with index b.
وكان 1 هو القيمة ذات المؤشر b في المتسلسلة .
So in summary, adding a data frame to a series,
وبشكل ملخص، تؤدي إضافة إطار بيانات لمتسلسلة إلى إضافة كل قيمة من المتسلسلة
adds each value of the series to one column of the data frame.
إلى أحد أعمدة إطار .البيانات
And it matches up the series to the dataframe using the index of the series
ويطابق هذا المتسلسلة بإطار البيانات باستخدام مؤشر المتسلسلة وأسماء الأعمدة بإطار البيانات
and the column names of the dataframe.
.